Guide to the Robert Hammond Papers ca. 1949-1998 MSS.164
Fales Library and Special Collections
Robert Hammond Papers
ca. 1949-1998
Fales Library and Special Collections
Hammond, Robert M. (Robert Morris), 1920-2009
MSS.164
12 Linear Feet (14 boxes)
Robert Hammond (1920-2009) was an educator and author in French literature and cinema. He taught at the University of Arizona-Tuscon, Harvard University, and SUNY-Cortland, where he also served as chair of the International Communications and Culture Department. Hammond wrote numerous plays, published analyses and criticisms of French filmography, translated various texts, and contributed to the scholarship on French theater and cinema. The Robert Hammond Papers contain original manuscripts of plays, books, articles, interviews, correspondence and other collected works of Hammond.
Provenance
The Robert Hammond Papers were donated to the Fales Library in 1995 by Robert Hammond.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note
Robert Hammond (b. 1920) was Professor Emeritus of French Literature and Cinema at SUNY-Cortland. He earned a BA from the University of Rochester (1942), and both an MA (1947) and PhD (1952) from Yale University. He was awarded a Fulbright Fellowship to France (1949-1950) along with numerous other honors, fellowships and grants. Hammond was an instructor, and then professor of French at the University of Arizona-Tuscon (1953-1967). He later was professor of French at Harvard University (1965-1966), and a visiting professor of French Literature and Cinema at Wells College in Aurora, NY (1967-1968). After 1968 Hammond taught at SUNY-Cortland, where he also served as chair of the International Communications and Culture Department.
Along with being a dedicated instructor, Hammond published numerous analyses and critiques of French literature and films, translated texts between French and English, and contributed countless papers and general scholarship on the French cinema. Much of Hammond's extensive scholarly work focused on French filmmaker Jean Cocteau, and his bilingual edition of Cocteau's Beauty and the Beast (NYU Press, 1970) is widely cited within the academy. Hammond wrote over 40 plays in both English and French and various other works of both poetry and prose. Hammond died in May 2009 in Paris, France.
Scope and Content Note
The Robert Hammond Papers consist of 14 boxes or approximately 12 linear feet of materials. The majority of the collection represents original manuscripts of plays, films, books and other prose authored by Hammond. Most contain various drafts and formats of a particular item, including handwritten pages, typed or mimeographed sheets, both bound and unbound. The Papers also include the work of other authors and playwrights, most notably a collection of plays written by Pascal Vrebos, a friend of Hammond. Also included with the Papers are research materials, reviews & news clippings, production notes and receipts, correspondence, and other various notes and annotations regarding his creative works. The majority of the collection is in English, with some French manuscripts where noted.
SERIES 1: Manuscripts: Play and Film Scripts
Series I contains numerous drafts and formats of various play and film scripts. Series 1 consists of 6 boxes (8 linear feet) and is divided into 5 subseries.
Subseries I.A contains five boxes of scripts written by Robert Hammond.
Subseries I.B contains scripts written by Pascal Vrebos
Subseries I.C contains scripts written by various other authors
Subseries I.D contains scripts of unidentified authorship (presumably by Hammond)
Subseries I.E contains various notes regarding unwritten plays
SERIES II: Manuscripts: Prose
Series II contains numerous drafts and formats of various fiction and non-fiction books and articles. Series II consists of 2 boxes (3 linear feet) and is divided into 4 subseries.
Subseries II.A contains prose written by Robert Hammond.
Subseries II.B contains prose written by various other authors
Subseries II.C contains prose of unidentified authorship (presumably by Hammond)
Subseries II.D contains various notes regarding unwritten prose
SERIES III: Interviews
Series III contains interviews conducted by Robert Hammond and is divided into 2 subseries.
Subseries III.A contains written interviews conducted by Robert Hammond.
Subseries III.B contains 28 audiocassettes of interviews conducted by Robert Hammond
SERIES IV: Miscellaneous
Series IV contains various printed material and media and is divided into 3 subseries.
Subseries IV.A contains various French cinema publications featuring screenplays and directors.
Subseries IV.B contains various French cinema promotional materials
Subseries IV.C contains one box of: diskettes containing various correspondence, audio tapes and a large-format, dated database printout of the Hammond Film Script Archive
SERIES V: Correspondence
Series V contains 1 box (1.5 linear feet) of correspondence Robert Hammond received from various professional and personal acquaintances.
SERIES VI: Production Photos
Series VI contains original production photos (along with photocopies) of three French films.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject within each subseries.
The files are grouped into 6 series:
Missing Title
Series I: Manuscripts, Play and Film Scripts
Series II: Manuscripts, Prose
Series III: Interviews
Series IV: Miscellaneous
Series V: Correspondence
Series VI: Production Photos
Related Material at the Fales Library and Special Collections
Hammond Film Script Collection (MSS.076)
Aubrey Wisberg Papers (MSS.048)
E. L. Doctorow Papers (MSS.056)
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual and born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Clippings (information artifacts); New York (N.Y.).; Correspondence.; Reviews (document genre); Photographs.; Scripts (documents); Screenplays; Sound recordings.; Theater -- Production and direction.; Motion pictures |z France.; Playwriting.; Delannoy, Jean, 1908-2008; Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963; Barjansky, Michael; Vrebos, Pascal; Spaak, Charles, 1903-1975; Rohmer, Éric, 1920-2010; Hammond, Robert M. (Robert Morris), 1920-2009
- Series I: Manuscripts: Play and film scripts
  - Subseries A: Robert Hammond
    Scope and Contents note
    Play and film scripts written by Robert Hammond. Manuscripts are in English unless otherwise noted.
    - The Artful Doctor (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Artful Doctor (ver. 2: handwritten in notebook), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beirut 75 (ver. 1: handwritten), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Beirut 75 (ver. 2: typed copy with plot summary) (see also Series 2A, box 7, folder 19), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Big Stairway (ver. 1: handwritten), June 28, 1958, 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Big Stairway (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), Aug 10, 1958, 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Big Stairway (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), Aug 10, 1958, 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Big Stairway (ver. 3: typed copy, bound), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Big Stairway (ver. 4: typed copy, bound), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Blind Voyage (ver. 1: handwritten), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Blind Voyage (ver. 2: handwritten, bound), July 15, 1960, 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Blind Voyage (ver. 3: mimeograph copy, bound), 1960; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bon Voyage (ver. 1: mimeograph copy, bound), 1960; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bon Voyage (ver. 2: mimeograph originals), 1960; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bon Voyage (ver. 3: mimeograph copy, bound), 1960; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bon Voyage (ver. 4: director's production copy with annotations), 1961; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bon Voyage (production notes & receipts), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bon Voyage (film screenplay, typed), 1982; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bon Voyage (ver. 1: film screenplay, handwritten in notebook, French), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bon Voyage (ver. 2: film screenplay, handwritten with edits, French), undated; 31142040616222 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Charles and Alexis (handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Charles and Alexis (handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Charlie and the Four Kings (handwritten), Aug 13, 1960, 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Circe and the Impresario (ver. 1: handwritten), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Circe and the Impresario (ver. 2: handwritten in notebook), 1959; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Circe and the Impresario (ver. 3: mimeograph copy, bound), 1961; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Common Market Cousins (handwritten), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Common Market Cousins (typed) (see also Series 2B, box 8, folders 35 & 36), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Dance of the Old Men (ver. 1: handwritten), Sep 03, 1960, 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - The Dance of the [Little] Old Men (ver. 2: handwritten, bound), Sep 03, 1960, 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - The Dance of the Little Old Men (ver. 3: mimeograph copy, bound), Sep 03, 1960, 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - The Dream of the Life and Therefore (ver. 1: handwritten), Jul 08, 1961, 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - The Dream of the Life and Therefore (ver. 2: handwritten, bound), 1961; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - The Dream of the Life and Therefore (ver. 3: mimeograph masters)1961, 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - The Dream of the Life and Therefore (ver. 4: mimeograph copy, bound), 1961; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Druse (handwritten in notebooks), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - The Ember (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - The Ember (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - The Ember (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - The Ember (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Flora Tristan (handwritten & plot summary) (see also Series 2A, box 7, folder 11), undated; 31142040616230 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Flowers for a Maypole (ver. 1: handwritten), July 28, 1959, 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Flowers for a Maypole (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks), 1959; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Flowers for a Maypole (ver. 3: mimeograph masters), 1960; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Flowers for a Maypole (ver. 4: mimeograph copy, bound), 1960; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Flowers for a Maypole (ver. 5: director's copy with annotations), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Flowers for a Maypole (ver. 6: mimeograph copy, bound), Dec 30, 1959, 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Flowers for a Maypole (production notes & news clippings), 1961; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Hector's Farewell (ver. 1: handwritten sheets, unordered), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Hector's Farewell (ver. 2: handwritten), August 27, 1959, 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Hector's Farewell (ver. 3: mimeograph masters), 1960; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Hector's Farewell (ver. 4: mimeograph copy, bound), 1960; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Hector's Farewell (ver. 5: handwritten, bound, legal), 1960; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Hope: I Coughed on a Snowflake (handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), 1939-1998; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Hope: I Coughed on a Snowflake (handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), 1939-1998; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Hope of the Hopis (handwritten in notebooks), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Inside Out (ver. 1: handwritten), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Inside Out (ver. 2: handwritten), 1964; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Johann Sebastian Schmidt (handwritten), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Johann Sebastian Schmidt or, A Teacher Passes (handwritten in notebook), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Johann Sebastian Schmidt or, A Teacher Passes (typed, bound), 1964; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - The Man with the Happy Walk (ver. 1: handwritten), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - The Man with the Happy Walk (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - The Man with the Happy Walk (ver. 3: handwritten in notebooks), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - The Man with the Happy Walk (notes & sketches), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - The Matriarchs (ver. 1: handwritten), August 7, 1961, 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - The Matriarchs (ver. 2: typed copy), undated; 31142040616248 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - The Money Bag (ver. 1: handwritten in notebook), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - The Money Bag (ver. 2: typed), June 30, 1972, 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - The Money Bag (production notes, clippings, plot summary), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Mr. Clown (ver. 1: handwritten, incomplete), 1959; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Mr. Clown (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), 1959; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Mr. Clown (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), 1959; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Mr. Clown (ver. 3: typed copy, bound), 1959; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Mr. Clown (review of play), 1961; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Nine Points of the Law (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks), Apr 25, 1957, 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Nine Points of the Law (ver. 2: handwritten), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - The Nursery (ver. 1: mimeograph copy, bound), 1963; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - The Nursery (ver. 2: mimeograph copy, bound, alternate cover), 1963; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - The Nursery (ver. 3: mimeograph copy, bound, "revised"), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - The Nursery (ver. 4: carbon copy, bound), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - The Nursery (promotional poster & program, French), 1998; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - The Party (ver. 1: handwritten, legal), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - The Party (ver. 2: mimeograph copy), 1958; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Pop Korn (various TV scripts, handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Pop Korn (various TV scripts, handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Pop Korn (production notes and plot summaries), undated; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - The Pure (ver. 1: handwritten), July 14, 1959, 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - The Pure (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), 1959; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - The Pure (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), 1959; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - The Pure (ver. 3: typed, bound), 1959; 31142040616255 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - The Royal Italian Cafe (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), February 10, 1959, 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - The Royal Italian Cafe (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), 1959; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - The Royal Italian Cafe (ver. 2: handwritten), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - The Royal Italian Cafe (ver. 3: typed), 1959; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Siexta (ver. 1: handwritten), May 24, 1959, 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Siexta (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks), July 14, 1959, 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Siexta (ver. 3: typed, bound), 1959; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - The Sign of the Cabbage and the Rose, or, Under the Sign of the Stork, undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Solitaire (ver. 1: handwritten), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Solitaire (ver. 2: handwritten in notebooks), 1958; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Solitaire (ver. 3: mimeograph copy, bound), 1960; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Solitaire (ver. 4: typed photocopy), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Solitaire (production notes & news clippings) (see also Series 2A, box 8, folder 24), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Solitaire (French) (ver. 1: handwritten), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Solitaire (French) (ver. 2: typed), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Solitaire (French) (ver. 3: mimeograph copy, bound), 1960; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Solitaire (French) (ver. 4: mimeograph copy, alternate format), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Solitaire (French) (various typed sheets), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - That Austrian Bitch (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - That Austrian Bitch (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - That Austrian Bitch (ver. 2: typed), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - That Austrian Bitch (ver. 3: additional typed pages) (see also Series 2A, box 8, folders 25-26), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Tom, Dick and Harry (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Tom, Dick and Harry (ver. 2: photocopy of typed pages), 1958; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Utopia 69 (handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 2), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Utopia 69 (handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 2), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - The Walrus, the Camel and the Kangaroo (ver. 1: handwritten), 1962; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - The Walrus, the Camel and the Kangaroo (ver. 2: typed copy), undated; 31142040616263 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Subseries I.B: Pascal Vrebos
    Play scripts written by Pascal Vrebos. Manuscripts are in English unless otherwise noted.
    - L'Agenda Orange (French, typed), 1970-1971; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Entrechats (French, typed), 1977; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Entrechats (translated excerpts in English), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - L'Imbecile (French, typed), 1983; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Polycarpe Reincarnate (ver. 1: typed), 1973; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Polycarpe Reincarnate (ver. 2: typed, with annotations), 1973; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - Polycarpe Reincarnate (press releases, reviews, news clippings), 1977; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - A Proposal of Marriage (French & English trans, typed), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Reincarne-toi Polycarpe! (French, typed), 1973; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Sade-Sack, or, How to Live after the Asprocalisp (typed), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Sade-Sack, or, How to Live after the Asprocalisp (clippings, reviews), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - La Tete de Truc (French, typed), 1972; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - The Thirteen Marriage Proposals (typed), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Les Treize "Demandes en Mariage" (French), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Yalta 2000 (ver. 1: French, typed), 1975-1976; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Yalta 2000 (ver. 2: English translation), 1976; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Yalta 2000 (ver. 3: English, handwritten in notebooks), 1976; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - An Interview with the Author (Vrebos interview by Frank Hirschmann), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Subseries I.C: Various Authors
    Play scripts written by various other authors. Manuscripts are in English unless otherwise noted.
    - L'Extra - Montel, Michele (French, typed), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - The French Touch - Kraft, Ted (typed), 1958; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Les Mauvaises Recontres - Astruc, d'Alexandre (French, handwritten in notebook), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Project No. 6 - Finney, Charles (mimeograph copy, bound), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Project No. 6 - Finney, Charles (news clippings, reviews), 1962; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Project No. 6 - Finney, Charles (production notes & receipts), 1962-1962; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - The Simple Things - Mendoza, Hector (handwritten), 1960; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Subseries I.D: Unknown Authors
    Play scripts of unidentified authorship (presumably by Hammond). For scripts with no identifiable title, character names or other distinguishing labels are provided in quotation marks. Manuscripts are in English unless otherwise noted.
    - Rock Breaks Scissors / Broken Feather (handwritten), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Un Voyage a Cythere (ver. 1: handwritten), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Un Voyage a Cythere (ver. 2: mimeograph copy), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Untitled Play Script: "Priest, Angela" (handwritten & typed sheets), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Untitled Play Script: "Sarah, Bruno" (typed with annotations), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Untitled Dialogue: "Wells College" (typed with edits), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Untitled Play Script: "Hayloft, Richard, Thomas" (handwritten), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Untitled Play Script: "Sinbad, Aladdin" (typed pages, incomplete), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Untitled Play Scripts (handwritten in multiple notebooks), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Untitled Play Scripts (handwritten in multiple notebooks), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Subseries I.E: Notes on unwritten plays
    Various notes regarding unwritten plays
    - Notes on plays (various handwritten notes), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Notes on plays "to go to France" (various handwritten notes), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Oh! Susannah (handwritten notes on play idea), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Opus IV (clippings and documents related to Opus IV play event), 1961; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Proposed Plots for Failure to Declare Love (handwritten notes), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Untitled production notes (handwritten notations, sequences, etc), undated; 31142040616271 (Box 6, Folder 160)
- Series II: Manuscripts: Prose
  - Subseries II.A: Robert Hammond
    Prose written by Robert Hammond. Manuscripts are in English unless otherwise noted.
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (documentation of translation), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (French, typed translation) (1 of 7), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (French, typed translation) (2 of 7), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)